let's discuss the solution to our btb
and BHD quiz we have a BHD that has 16
entries and it's a one bit predictor
each of the entries is a single bit that
tells us what the last outcome was and
initially they start all at predicting
not taken the question was how many
mispredictions do we have for each
instruction initially the BHT says not
taken for all of the entries and we have
already seen that the BHT entries that
we will use are all different so these
branches and other instructions are not
going to interfere with each other each
of them just uses its own BHD entry
because the initial prediction is not
taken and this is indeed not a taken
Branch we have zero mispredictions here
same here when we enter the loop this
branch is actually not taken so we have
no misprediction the first time we
executed this instruction here is
predicted not taken the first time it's
not taken for real so every other time
that we execute it it's going to be
predicted not taken correctly so there
is zero mispredictions and same thing
happens here and here and here for this
Branch things are more
interesting the initial prediction in
the BHD is going to be not taken but
this branch is taken so we have a
misprediction the first time this branch
is taken then the BHD entry for that
instruction is updated to say taken so
every other time that we execute this
instruction it's correctly predicted as
taken so we have only the one Mis
prediction initially for this Branch
it's never taken until the very last
time the 10 and1st time we do it every
time it's not taken we have a correct
prediction because we start out in the
not taken state of the predictor and
just keep doing that the last time we
need to execute this Branch it is taken
and the last outcome that we have seen
was not taken so there will be again a
single misprediction here so as you can
see the one bit predictor is very
accurate we are executing a lot of
instructions this one is done 1001 times
this one is done 100 times these are
done 100 times each so for what amounts
to more than 600 instruction executions
we only have two mispredictions this
shows that the one bit predictor really
works well for things like Loops that
execute many
iterations however we will see later
that it doesn't work well for some of
the other things like for example Loops
that don't have many iterations or than
else is